<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dbatools on Rich In SQL</title>
    <link>https://richinsql.com/tags/dbatools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dbatools on Rich In SQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:30:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richinsql.com/tags/dbatools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Database Migration Using DbaTools</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2020-02-15-database-migration-using-dbatools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:30:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2020-02-15-database-migration-using-dbatools/</guid>
      <description>This post is mainly for me to look back on in the future and see how this was done, so I will keep it short. What I needed was a way to migrate an entire instance from one availability group to another, on two new servers with an entirely new availability group name, the test instance wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been that much of a problem as there is only around 10 databases on it however the production instance houses many many more databases with various logins and agent jobs for lots of different things that would have taken a really long time to move one by one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performing a database upgrade with dbatools</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-07-23-performing-a-database-upgrade-with-dbatools/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 18:00:43 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-07-23-performing-a-database-upgrade-with-dbatools/</guid>
      <description>I was recently asked to move one of our production databases to a staging server, this was to allow one of our suppliers to update the schema, once the update had been complete I needed to move the database back, our production server was running SQL Server 2012 in a two node availability group, the staging server was running SQL Server 2012 Express. Here is how I made all that happen with just a few lines of PowerShell using the fantastic dbatools.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking dbatools further</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-03-28-taking-dbatools-further/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2019 16:00:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-03-28-taking-dbatools-further/</guid>
      <description>Last week I wrote about how I was getting started with dbatools a lot has happened since then, I mean I have done some more reading and tried a few new things and I wanted to expand on some of the really cool things this module can do.
Tables here, tables there Some times for whatever reason I need to be able to script a table out, this involves loading up SSMS, connecting to the instance, getting to the database, right clicking…you get the idea it is a long drawn out task, but what if I could do that with just one line of code?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
