<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>mylife on Rich In SQL</title>
    <link>https://richinsql.com/tags/mylife/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mylife on Rich In SQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 09:00:31 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richinsql.com/tags/mylife/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Missing In Action</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2021-07-06-missing-in-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 09:00:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2021-07-06-missing-in-action/</guid>
      <description>It is no secret that the past 18 months has been a challenge for everyone, worldwide. I started this blog to document some of my learning along my journey as a developer but during the last 18 months so much has changed.
Let&amp;rsquo;s rewind a little bit, around March 2019 I was taken out of my post a a developer to superivse a team I had worked in when I first joined the orginisation, this team was the support desk, the plan from the management was that I would continue developing application code 2 days a week and look after the support desk 3 days a week, but in reality that never panned out the support desk was a full time position so I was never really given the time to develop any code during the working day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I Got Here &amp;#038; Where I am Going</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-08-28-how-i-got-here-where-i-am-going/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Aug 2018 17:55:31 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-08-28-how-i-got-here-where-i-am-going/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Grab a beverage of your choosing, you may be here for a while…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s warp back in time 15 years, leaving school I had no GCSE’s above grade C I had pretty much failed at school, I am not very good at tests you see, I perform better practically but when you leave school you academic status is not determined on a practical level, rather they use the results from these tests, I applied to college but was not able to do the course I had my heart set upon, well not right away anyway, I had to take some access courses in English…English to be able to attend a course in IT, all seemed a bit demotivating to say the least but I persevered, it was a real struggle, I found the pace really hard and at the end of that course I got my D up to a C and was able to take the course in IT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
