<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Server on Rich In SQL</title>
    <link>https://richinsql.com/tags/server/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Server on Rich In SQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:30:45 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richinsql.com/tags/server/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Database Migration Using DbaTools</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2020-02-15-database-migration-using-dbatools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 10:30:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2020-02-15-database-migration-using-dbatools/</guid>
      <description>This post is mainly for me to look back on in the future and see how this was done, so I will keep it short. What I needed was a way to migrate an entire instance from one availability group to another, on two new servers with an entirely new availability group name, the test instance wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been that much of a problem as there is only around 10 databases on it however the production instance houses many many more databases with various logins and agent jobs for lots of different things that would have taken a really long time to move one by one.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exporting Database Names To CSV</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-09-15-exporting-database-names-to-csv/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2019 11:30:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-09-15-exporting-database-names-to-csv/</guid>
      <description>I needed a way of getting a complete list of databases over multiple instances in SQL Server into something that I was able to manipulate, of course I could load up SSMS and run a query against the MSDB database to return me the name of every database on that instance, but that is slow, I have to connect to each instance I want to query an individually run the code;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Agent Jobs in Availability Groups</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-09-03-managing-agent-jobs-in-availability-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 10:00:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-09-03-managing-agent-jobs-in-availability-groups/</guid>
      <description>Availability groups and SQL Server Agent Jobs, how do you go about managing them? In our environment we have two availability group members, for the purposes of this post we will call them S1 and S2 one is always primary and the other is the read-only secondary if the availability group fails over the roles will change, but you knew that right?
So S1 is the primary and S2 is the secondary, I had a number of SQL Server Agent jobs that existed on both members, the job would run on both members but always fail on the secondary, as my jobs are setup to alert when the job fails we were getting alerted that the job had failed on S2 but really it hadn’t it just wasn’t able to run on S2 because that was in a read-only state.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
