<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>SQLAgent on Rich In SQL</title>
    <link>https://richinsql.com/tags/sqlagent/</link>
    <description>Recent content in SQLAgent on Rich In SQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 07:46:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richinsql.com/tags/sqlagent/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Check If Database Mail Is Running</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-09-28-check-is-database-mail-if-running/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Sep 2018 07:46:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-09-28-check-is-database-mail-if-running/</guid>
      <description>So, recently I ran into a problem where I wasn’t getting any alerts for any of my SQL Agent Jobs, it didn’t take very long to get to the bottom of the problem but upon investigating it turned out that DBMail was actually in a STOPPED state, which was weird, this particular server had been rebooted the day before but SQL Agent was running so why was DBMail stopped? The error log didn’t prove too helpful on this one so I used;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Agent Jobs in Availability Groups</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-09-03-managing-agent-jobs-in-availability-groups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Sep 2018 10:00:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-09-03-managing-agent-jobs-in-availability-groups/</guid>
      <description>Availability groups and SQL Server Agent Jobs, how do you go about managing them? In our environment we have two availability group members, for the purposes of this post we will call them S1 and S2 one is always primary and the other is the read-only secondary if the availability group fails over the roles will change, but you knew that right?
So S1 is the primary and S2 is the secondary, I had a number of SQL Server Agent jobs that existed on both members, the job would run on both members but always fail on the secondary, as my jobs are setup to alert when the job fails we were getting alerted that the job had failed on S2 but really it hadn’t it just wasn’t able to run on S2 because that was in a read-only state.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
