<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VisualStudio on Rich In SQL</title>
    <link>https://richinsql.com/tags/visualstudio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VisualStudio on Rich In SQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richinsql.com/tags/visualstudio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Installing Visual Studio SQL Intergration Services</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2021-08-09-installing-visual-studio-sql-server-intergration-services/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Aug 2021 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2021-08-09-installing-visual-studio-sql-server-intergration-services/</guid>
      <description>In this post, I am going to show you how to install SQL Server Intergration services for Visual Studio 2019, SSDT or SQL Server Data Tools no longer exists for Visual Studio 2019 so installation is a little bit different for newer versions of Visual Studio.
First we are going to need to make sure we have Data Storage &amp;amp; Processing installed, Open up Visual Studio and select Create New Blank Project, from the bottom of the template window select Install more tools and features as shown below;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a dynamically populated Grid View</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-06-24-creating-a-dynamically-populated-grid-view/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jun 2019 16:00:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-06-24-creating-a-dynamically-populated-grid-view/</guid>
      <description>I haven’t published a post here in what feels like an eternity, I came across a problem recently and wasn’t sure how to go about writing the code, what I had was a form which consisted of a number of drop-down boxes and I needed to get the values of the drop-down boxes into a GridView, then loop that GridView to insert that data into a database.
The problem was I also needed to allow for a row to be removed from the Grid View if the user decided the data selected was no longer required.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
