<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>windows on Rich In SQL</title>
    <link>https://richinsql.com/tags/windows/</link>
    <description>Recent content in windows on Rich In SQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 08:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richinsql.com/tags/windows/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Install Jekyll On Windows Using Linux Subsystem</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2020-04-19-jekyll-windows-linux-subsystem/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Apr 2020 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2020-04-19-jekyll-windows-linux-subsystem/</guid>
      <description>I recently moved to a new development workstation at home, still using Windows 10 but it was a fresh install. All of the previously installed dependencies were gone, including Ruby &amp;amp; Jekyll for which this site is built.
I tried installing Ruby from the official binaries but kept running into dependency errors when trying to serve the site locally, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure it out, so I decided to see if I could get it working using the Linux Subsystem for Windows, TL;DR it worked perfectly, but wanted to share how I went about setting it up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing SQL Management Studio On Another Drive</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-11-15-installing-sql-management-studio-on-another-drive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Nov 2018 07:14:50 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-11-15-installing-sql-management-studio-on-another-drive/</guid>
      <description>So you have that really fast SSD in your development machine or that machine that is provided by your workplace, windows is installed onto it thus that is where the C: resides, the problem is that SSD is only 120GB in size, windows takes up a large chunk of that and once you install a few tools like Visual Studio, SQL Server Developer and SQL Management Studio that lovely SSD is pretty much full.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
