<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal on Rich In SQL</title>
    <link>https://richinsql.com/tags/personal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal on Rich In SQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richinsql.com/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Using Chocolatey</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2021-07-12-using-chocolatey/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jul 2021 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2021-07-12-using-chocolatey/</guid>
      <description>One of the most time consuming tasks when configuring a new computer is installing all of the applications that I use on a day to day basis, I am sure that everyone has this very same problem, but recently I came accross a package manager for Windows called Chocolatey, I am sure this has been around for absoloutely ages, looking at the amount of packages that are available but for me it is still pretty new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rebuilding My Workstation</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2020-09-27-rebuilding-my-workstation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2020-09-27-rebuilding-my-workstation/</guid>
      <description>This year has been incredibly strange to try and bring back some kind of normality I decided to rebuild my home workstation, this post will serve as the log for that project.
What I had before Before I started this project I was making use of a refurbished Dell Optiplex 7020 with an i7 2600 processor, 16GB of 2400 ram, a SSD for the main operating system disk and a 1TB Western Digital which we would later re-purpose.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Current 2019 Setup</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-07-06-my-current-setup-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 14:17:13 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-07-06-my-current-setup-19/</guid>
      <description>I have never done a my setup post here before, I don’t think it ever occurred to me that it might be something that people would be interested in, however my home workstation is now in a place that I am happy to share.
It is not by any stretch perfect, and there are some things that I would like to change but here it is, as of July 2019.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
