<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>C# on Rich In SQL</title>
    <link>https://richinsql.com/tags/c#/</link>
    <description>Recent content in C# on Rich In SQL</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 16:00:04 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://richinsql.com/tags/c#/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Building a Formula One Race Tracker – Part Three</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-04-23-building-a-formula-one-race-tracker-part-three/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2019 16:00:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-04-23-building-a-formula-one-race-tracker-part-three/</guid>
      <description>Contents
 Part One – Project Overview Part Two – Database Schema Part Three – Stored Procedures  Stored Procedures are going to power the flow of data in and out of the Formula One Race Tracker, I will make use of a stored procedure for sending my data into the application and I am also going to make use of a stored procedure for getting the data back out again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Formula One Race Tracker &amp;#8211; Part Two</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-04-16-building-a-formula-one-race-tracker-part-two/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2019 16:00:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-04-16-building-a-formula-one-race-tracker-part-two/</guid>
      <description>Contents
 Part One – Project Overview Part Two – Database Schema  The Database Schema In Part One we looked at the project scope, why I was building this project, how the database was going to look, the columns and their respective datatypes and a mock-up of the application design, in this part I am going to show you how I went about populating the database with the objects required and then filling them objects with referential data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a Formula One Race Tracker &amp;#8211; Part One</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-04-09-building-a-formula-one-race-tracker-part-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2019 16:00:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2019-04-09-building-a-formula-one-race-tracker-part-one/</guid>
      <description>Contents
 Part One – Project Overview Part Two – Database Schema  A little while ago I answered a question over on StackOverflow from someone who was asking how they could design a database that would allow them to track individual races in a Formula One season, this question formed the foundation for this series of posts which will hopefully demonstrate my building process of a small simplistic web application, using a lot of what I have learned over the last five years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Directory Searcher &amp;#038; Ambiguous Name Resoloution</title>
      <link>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-09-08-directory-searcher-ambiguous-name-resoloution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 12:12:57 +0100</pubDate>
      <author>hello@richinsql.com (Rich)</author>
      <guid>https://richinsql.com/posts/2018-09-08-directory-searcher-ambiguous-name-resoloution/</guid>
      <description>Recently I was writing a login process that required me to query Active Directory, admittedly something I have never done before, I took to the internet to search for a solution on how this was going to work and came across the following query string to use within my existing class.
search.Filter = &amp;#34;(&amp;amp;(objectCategory=person)(objectClass=user)(anr=&amp;#34; + Username + &amp;#34;)(!userAccountControl:1.2.840.113556.1.4.803:=2))&amp;#34;; I set to test this with multiple users, and it worked perfectly, the correct data was returned in 100% of the test cases that I had tried, so the code got moved into production and signed off.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
